#### **Howard Jess**

#### Web Application UI/UX Developer

hjess@mail.com linkedin.com/in/hjess 206.412.9924

#### Brief

I thrive and excel in a collaborative team environment; after many experiences in desktop applications, system programming, and networking infrastructure, I settled into web application UI development as an interesting intersection of them all. I'm especially interested in user experience, elegant design, and accessibility.

#### **Skills**

Tools:

Bourne shell, GIMP, Git, VIM

Languages:

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS (Less, SASS/SCSS), TCL, C

Systems:

Linux, Unix, Mac OS/X, Windows

**Technologies:** 

Bootstrap, Element UI, DOM, HTTP, i18n/l10n, jQuery, Knockout, MVC, REST, TCP/IP, Vue.js

**Development:** 

Agile, Scrum, Kanban

# Experience

# **Trupanion**

Front-end Web Application Developer

April 2017 → June 2023

Javascript, Typescript, Vue, SCSS, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, Razor (C# templates), SignalR, ASP.Net, Git

Brought in as Trupanion's first UI specialist. Projects

- Member Portal (lead UI dev): provides customer access to their account. VanillaJS/Typescript/jQuery/Vue, Sass
- Website 3.0 (UI team member): main public-facing website; part of a rewrite team. VanillaJS/jQuery, Sass, Sitecore
- <u>VetPortal</u> (lead UI dev): veterinary hospital software. Full rewrite from VanillaJS/jQuery/KnockoutJS/Kendo to Vue/Bootstrap, reduced network payload by 50%
- Hospital Management Tool (sole UI dev): internal support for VetPortal. Vue, Element
- Partner Portal (sole UI dev): allows State Farm agents to create & manage their portfolio of Trupanion policies.
   Vue
- Agent Reassignment Tool (sole UI dev): allow State Farm managers to manage policy re-distribution among agents. Vue

### **Navigating Cancer** (contract position)

Front-end Web Application Developer

June 2016 → February 2017

Bootstrap, Coffeescript, Backbone is, HAML, JSON Schema, JSON Editor, Mocha, Ruby on Rails, SASS

Developer for Navigating Cancer's suite of Patient Care Management software, dedicated to improving and streamlining the relationship and care experience for cancer patients and oncology clinics. Projects:

- Complex Triage Pathways: implemented a set of <u>JSON Schema</u>+<u>JSON Editor</u>-based dynamic forms to standardize symptom data recording for cancer patients
- · Living Style Guide: continued work to maintain and upgrade the development group's style and component library

# **Howard Jess**

### Web Application UI/UX Developer

hjess@mail.com linkedin.com/in/hjess 206.412.9924

# Rosetta Stone (acquired Livemocha in April 2013)

Front-end Web Application Developer
November 2012 → April 2016
AngularJS, CouchDB, HTML, Javascript, Mixpanel, SCSS, Sproutcore

Developer for Rosetta Stone's <u>Advanced English for Business</u> language-learning application, and <u>Livemocha</u>, a social community-based language-learning application. Projects:

- · Password reset/recovery
- · User profile management
- Partner connections
- Analytics, using Mixpanel Analytics
- Full language-learning engine (a <u>SPA</u>) rewrite from <u>Sproutcore</u> to <u>AngularJS</u>.

# Optify, Inc.

Front-end Software Engineer September 2011 → October 2012 Backbone.js, HTML, Javascript, LESS, Mixpanel

UI developer for Optify's Inbound Marketing software suite, a <u>SAAS</u> tool for B2B marketers. Projects:

- Customer site "Landing Page" editor/publisher
- Contact Manager & Email Manager tools
- Analytics, using Mixpanel Analytics
- · Rewrote UI coding standards document, and overhauled the Javascript library namespace

# Cobalt.com, Inc.

Senior UI Developer September 2009 → September 2011

Lead UI developer on Cobalt's *New Products* team, charged with creating and delivering innovative website products for sale to auto manufacturers and dealers. Projects:

- · Embedded Google maps for location pages
- Facebook and Twitter publishing and feed widgets
- Embedded YouTube player/playlist handler
- Initial implementation of front-end unit testing using jstestdriver

# **Education**

#### **Northwestern University**

B.A., Economics